My mom is a strong black woman
أمي امرأة سمراء قوية
who raised her kids to have the same sense of strength and pride.
ربت أطفالها ليكون لديهم نفس الشعور بالقوة والفخر.
This spirit was epitomized by a single wall
هذه الروح تجسدت على جدار واحد
in our small, two-bedroom apartment on the South Side of Chicago.
في شقتنا الصغيرة، ذات الغرفتين في جنوب شيكاغو.
Two pictures hung proudly:
حيث عُلقت صورتان بفخر:
one larger-than-life photo of my siblings and I
الصورة الكبيرة لي مع إخوتي
and the other a picture of my mom
والصورة الأخرى لأمي
at 12 years old
في عمر الثانية عشر
staring into the eyes of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.
تُحدق بعيني د. مارتن لوثر كنج الابن.
When I was younger, I used to stand on my tippy-toes,
عندما كنت صغيرة، اعتدت الوقوف على أصابع قدمي.
stare at that picture,
أُحدق بهذه الصورة،
close my eyes tightly, and just pretend that it was me
أغمض عيني، وأتخيل أنني مكانها
who marched on Washington and who transformed a generation
الذي خرج في مسيرة إلى واشنطن وحول جيلًا
by his words, "I have a dream."
بجملته " لدي حلم".
But I did get to meet him.
ولكنني استطعت أن ألتقيه.
Now, obviously, I didn't meet Dr. King,
بالتأكيد، أنا لم ألتق د. كينج،
but I met a man named Dr. Vincent Harding.
لكني التقيت برجل يدعى د. فنسنت هاردينغ.
He worked with Dr. King from day one
عمل مع د. كنج منذ اليوم الأول.
and even wrote some of his most iconic speeches.
وحتى كتب بعض خطبه الشهيرة.
You see, this was a really important moment for me as a kid,
كما ترون، هذه كانت حقا لحظة مهمة لي كطفلة،
because it was the first time that I realized
لأنها كانت أول مرة أدرك فيها
that it wasn't just Dr. King who led this revolution,
أنه لم يكن د. كينج من قاد هذه الثورة،
but he was surrounded by a movement made up of anonymous extraordinaries.
لكنه كان محاط بحركة تكونت من أناس استثنائيين مجهولين.
Anonymous extraordinaries are people who work selflessly and vigorously
الاستثنائيون المجهولون هم أشخاص يعملون للغير وبنشاط
for what they believe in,
من أجل ما يؤمنون به،
people who are motivated by conviction and not recognition.
أُناس تدفعهم القناعة وليس الشهرة.
It took me a long time to realize the significance of this moment,
احتجت لوقت طويل لأُدرك مغزى هذه اللحظة،
until I was much older.
إلى أن أصبحت أكبر سنًّا.
And like I said, I grew up in Chicago.
وكما ذكرت، فقد نشأت في شيكاغو.
I grew up in a rough, poor neighborhood,
نشأت في حي قاسٍ وفقير،
but it didn't really matter to me as kid
لكن ذلك لم يعنيني كثيراً كطفلة
because I literally have the most incredible family in the world.
لأنه حرفيا كان لدي أعظم أسرة في العالم.
Two things that I did struggle with a lot
الأمران اللذان عانيت منهما كثيرًا
growing up was one --
خلال نشأتي...
that my dad has been sick my whole life.
الأول، أن والدي كان مريضًا طوال حياتي.
He suffers from Parkinson's and pancreatitis,
لقد عانى من الشلل الرعاش والتهاب البنكرياس،
and as a kid, it was so hard for me to watch my hero
وكطفلة، كان من الصعب علي مشاهدة بطلي
in so much pain.
يتألم كثيراً.
And my other issue was with me.
والأمر الآخر كان متعلقا بي
I guess you could say I had an identity crisis.
أظن أنه يمكنكم القول أني أعاني أزمة هوية.
I had to move four times during high school,
كان علي التنقل 4 مرات خلال المدرسة الثانوية
and my freshman year I went to an extremely racist high school.
في سنتي الأولى التحقت بمدرسة عنصرية جدا.
Kids were so cruel.
كان الأطفال وقحين جدا.
They gave us hate letters,
وأعطونا رسائل كراهية،
wrote terrible things on our lockers
وكتبوا أشياء فظيعة على خزاناتنا
and because I'm biracial, they would tell me,
ولأني ثنائية العرق، كانوا يقولون لي،
"You can't be both. You have to choose, black or white."
"لا يمكن أن تكوني الاثنين. يجب أن تختاري، بيضاء أو سوداء."
And in the end I just resented being either.
وفي النهاية، استأت أن أكون الاثنين.
And then all of a sudden, my senior year rolls around, 2008,
وفجأة، حان وقت تخرجي سنة 2008،
and being mixed, being racially ambiguous is this new cool fad,
وأصبح كونك مختلطًا وغامض العرق هو الموضة الجديدة الرائعة.
like, "Natalie, now it's OK for you to like you. You're pretty now."
مثلا، " ناتالي، الآن لا بأس أن تحبي نفسك. أنت الآن جميلة."
I was over it. I was tired of caring about what other people thought
كنت قد تجاوزته. وقد تعبت من الاهتمام بأفكار الناس
and I just wanted to hurry up,
و أردت فقط الإسراع،
go through my classes, whatever school I was going to be at next,
أن أحضر فصولي، مهما كانت المدرسة التي كنت سأذهب إليها في المرحلة التالية،
and graduate.
وأتخرج.
It wasn't until I was 17
ولم يحدث ذلك إلى أن بلغت سن 17
and I saw a film called "Invisible Children"
وشاهدت فيلمًا يسمى "الأطفال المخفيون"
that something happened.
حدث شيء ما
Child soldiers,
الأطفال الجنود،
children as young as my nephews
أطفال صغار بعمر أبناء أخوتي
being abducted, given AK-47s and forced to kill,
اختطفوا وأُعطوا أسلحة وأُجبروا على القتال،
not just anyone, but oftentimes forced to kill their own parents,
وليس أي شخص، بل أجبروا أحيانا على قتل أبائهم،
their own siblings --
وأشقائهم...
a rebel army committing mass murder for no political or religious reason,
جيش المتمردين ارتكب جريمة قتل جماعي بدون سبب سياسي أو ديني،
just because.
فقط هكذا.
25 years.
25 سنة.
25 years this conflict has been going on.
استمر هذا الصراع خلال 25 سنة.
I'm 20 years old,
عمري 20 سنة،
so that makes this conflict five years older than me.
إذن هذا الصراع يكبرني بخمس سنوات.
One man,
رجل واحد،
one man with one charismatic voice,
رجل واحد بصوت مميز،
started this whole thing.
بدأ كل هذا،
His name is Joseph Kony.
اسمه جوزيف كوني.
When I saw this film, something happened.
عندما شاهدت هذا الفيلم، حدث شيء ما.
Something started kind of stirring inside of me,
بدأ إحساس ما يخالجني،
and I couldn't identify what it was.
ولم أستطع تحديد ما هو.
I didn't know if it was rage, if it was pity,
لم أعرف ما إذا كان غضب أم شفقة،
if I felt guilty because this was the first time
إن كان شعور بالذنب فلأنها أول مرة
I'd heard about a 25-year-long war.
أسمع فيها عن حرب امتدت 25 سنة.
I couldn't even give it a name.
لم أستطع أن أصف ذلك الإحساس.
All I knew is that it kicked me off my ass and I started asking questions.
كل ما أعرفه أنه أيقظ وجداني وبدأت أتسائل.
What do I do? What can one 17-year-old do?
ماذا أفعل؟ ماذا تستطيع فتاة في 17 أن تفعل؟
You've got to give me something.
يجب أن تعطوني شيئا ما.
And they gave me something.
وقد أعطوني شيئا.
The founders and filmmakers at Invisible Children told me
أخبرني مؤسسو ومنتجو فيلم الأطفال المخفيون
that there was this bill,
أن هناك مشروع قانون،
that if we could just get this bill passed,
إن استطعنا تمريره،
it would do two things: one, it would apprehend Joseph Kony
سيتحقق أمران: الأول، سيتم القبض على جوزيف كوني
and the top commanders in his rebel army,
وكبار القادة في جيشه المتمرد،
and two, it would provide funding for the recovery of these regions
وثانيًّا، سيتم توفير دعم لعملية إصلاح تلك المناطق
that had been devastated by 25 years of war.
التي دمرت بفعل حرب دامت 25 سنة.
And I was like, done. Let me at it.
فقلت: " حسنا. دعوا الأمر لي.
I swear I will do whatever I can to make this happen.
أُقسم أني سأفعل كل ما في وسعي ليتم ذلك."
So myself and 99 other idealistic 18- to 20-year-olds
إذا أنا و99 شخص مثاليون بين 18و 20 سنة
hopped on a plane to intern in San Diego with Invisible Children.
ركبنا طائرة متجهة إلى سان دييغو للتدرب مع الأطفال المخفيون.
I was postponing college. We weren't getting paid for this
لقد أجلت الكلية. ولم نحصل على مقابل لفعل ذلك.
and you could call it irresponsible or crazy -- my parents did.
ويمكنكم أن تقولوا أنه تصرف غير مسؤول أو مجنون ... كما قال أبوي.
But for us, it would have been insane not to go.
لكن بالنسبة لنا، كان من الجنون عدم الذهاب.
We all felt this urgency, and we would do whatever it took
جميعنا شعرنا بالحاجه لفعل ذلك، وأننا سنفعل كل ما يمكن
to pass this bill.
لتمرير هذا القانون.
So we were given our first task.
وبالتالي تم إعطاؤنا أول مهمة.
We were going to plan an event called the Rescue of Joseph Kony's Child Soldiers
وكنا سنخطط لحدث يدعى "إنقاذ الأطفال المجندين عند جوزيف كوني"
where participants would come in a hundred cities worldwide
حيث كان سيحضر مشاركون من مئات المدن حول العالم
and rally in their city center
ويتجمعوا بمركز المدينة
until a celebrity or a political figure
إلى أن يقررأحد المشاهير أو السياسيين
came and used their voice on behalf of these child soldiers,
الحضور واستخدام صوته لمساعدة الأطفال المجندين،
and at that point each city was "rescued."
وفي تلك اللحظة ستشارك كل مدينة وستكون "منقذة."
But the catch was, we weren't leaving the cities until we were rescued.
ولكن الفكرة كانت، أننا لن نغادر المدن إلى أن يتم تحريرنا.
I was given Chicago and nine other cities
كنت مسؤولة على شيكاغو وتسع مدن أخرى
and I told my bosses, I was like,
وأخبرت رؤسائي، أنني أعتقد أنه
"If we're going for big-name people, why not go for the queen bee? Right?
"إذا كنا سنسعى لجذب انتباه أشخاص مهمين، لما لا نستهدف ملكة النحل؟ صح؟
Why not go for Oprah Winfrey?"
لما لا نلجأ إلى أُوبرا وينفري؟"
They thought I was a little idealistic, but I mean, we were trying to think big.
ظنوا أني أفكر بمثالية قليلا، لكننا كنا نفكر بشكل كبير.
We were doing an impossible thing,
كنا نفعل أمرًا مستحيلًا،
so why not try to reach more impossible things?
بالتالي لما لا نحاول بلوغ أمور أخرى مستحيلة؟
And so we had from January to April to get this done.
كان لدينا من يناير إلى أبريل لإنجاز ذلك.
This is the number of hours that I spent on logistics,
هذا عدد الساعات التي قضيتها في التخطيط والتنفيذ،
from getting permits to rallying participants
من الحصول على التصاريح إلى جمع المشاركين
and finding venues.
وإيجاد أماكن.
This is the number of times that I was rejected
هذه عدد المرات التي رُفِضْتُ فيها
by celebrities' agents or politicians' secretaries.
من قِبل وكلاء المشاهير أو مساعدي السياسين.
That is amount of money that I spent personally
وهذا مقدار المال الذي أنفقته شخصياَ
on Red Bull and Diet Coke to stay awake during this movement.
على ريد بول وكولا دايت لأبقى مستيقظة خلال هذه الحركة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You can judge me if you want to.
يمكنكم انتقادي إذا أردتم.
That is my hospital bill from the kidney infection I got
هذه فاتورة مستشفى متعلقة بالتهاب الكلى الذي أصابني
from an overconsumption of caffeine due to this event.
من كثرة استهلاك الكافيين بسبب هذا الحدث.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
These were just some of the ridiculous things that we did
هذه فقط بعض الأشياء السخيفة التي قمنا بها
to try and pull this event off.
لمحاولة إنجاح هذا الحدث.
And so April 21 rolls around and the event begins.
وصل ال21 من أبريل وبدأ الحدث.
A hundred cities around the world. They were beautiful.
مائة مدينة من حول العالم. كانوا رائعين.
Six days later, all the cities were rescued but one:
بعد ستة أيام، جميع المدن شاركت في الإنقاذ عدا واحدة:
Chicago.
شيكاغو.
So we were waiting in the city.
بالتالي كنا ننتظر في المدينة.
People started coming from all over the world,
بدأ الناس يحضرون من جميع أنحاء العالم،
all over the country to be reinforcements
من جميع أنحاء البلاد لتقديم الدعم
and join their voice with ours.
ضم أصواتهم لأصواتنا.
And finally, on May 1,
وأخيرا، في فاتح ماي، تمركزنا حول استوديو أُوبرا
and we got her attention.
وحصلنا على انتباهها.
This is a clip from a film called "Together We Are Free"
هذا مقطع من فيلم "معاً نحن أحرار"
documenting the rescue event and my attempt to get Oprah.
يوثق حدث الإنقاذ ومحاولتي لمقابلة أوبرا،
(Video) Oprah Winfrey: When I drove into the office,
(فيديو) أوبرا وينفري: عندما وصلتُ إلى المكتب،
there was a giant -- when you came in, was there a group outside?
كان هناك حشد كبير ... عندما جئتم، هل كانت هناك مجموعة بالخارج؟
Crowd: Yes.
الجمهور : نعم.
OW: Holding up signs asking if I would talk to them
أوبرا: كانوا يحملون لافتات تطلب مني التحدث معهم
for just five minutes,
لخمس دقائق فقط،
so I was happy to do so.
كنت سعيدة بفعل ذلك.
And they are with a group called "Invisible Children,"
وكانوا مع مجموعة تدعى "الأطفال المخفيين"،
and I told this group outside
وأخبرت المجموعة التي بالخارج
that I'd give them a minute to state their case.
أنني سأخصص لهم دقيقة لعرض قضيتهم.
Man: Oprah, thank you so much for having us.
رجل: أُوبرا، شكرا جزيلاً لاستقبالنا.
Basically, these folks out here have seen the story of 30,000 children
أساسا، هؤلاء الناس بالخارج شاهدوا قصة 30 ألف طفل
abducted by a rebel leader named Joseph Kony.
اختطفوا بواسطة قائد التمرد المدعو جوزيف كوني.
And they're out here in solidarity,
وهم الآن هنا متضامنين،
and they have been out here for six days.
وكانوا كذلك لستة أيام.
This started 100,000 people worldwide.
بدأ هذا بمئة ألف شخص حول العالم.
Now it's down to 500 standing strong
الآن أصبحنا حوالي 500 شخص صامدين
so that you can raise the profile of this issue
لكنك نستطيع زيادة الاهتمام بهذه القضية
and we can end the longest-running war in Africa and rescue those kids
وإنهاء أطول حرب في أفريقيا وإنقاذ أولئك الأطفال
that are child soldiers still in East Africa.
الذين لا يزال تجنيدهم مستمرًّا في شرق أفريقيا.
Oprah, I have to say this girl Natalie here,
أوبرا، علي أن أقول أن هذه الفتاة ناتالي،
she's 18 years old.
هي في الثامنة عشر.
She was an intern for us this year,
كانت متدربة لدينا في هذا العام،
and she said, "My one goal is to get Oprah."
وقد قالت، "هدفي الأول هو الوصول لأوبرا."
She had 2,000 people come out on Saturday,
جعلت ألفين شخص يخرجون يوم السبت،
but it rained.
لكن مع تساقط الأمطار.
She stood here in the rain with 50 people.
بقيت تحت المطر مع 50 شخصا.
When they heard she was here, hundreds started coming.
وعندما سمعوا أنها ماتزال هنا، بدأ المئات بالحضور.
People are here from Mexico, Australia.
الناس هنا من المكسيك وأستراليا.
Natalie's 18.
ناتالي في الثامنة عشر.
Don't think you're too young.
ألا تعتقدين أنك صغيرة جدا.
You can change the world any day.
تستطيعون تغيير العالم في أي يوم.
Start now.
ابدأ الآن.
Start today.
ابدأ اليوم.
(Cheers)
(هتاف)
Man: Was it worth it?
رجل: ألم يستحق الأمر هذا العناء؟
Crowd: Yeah!
الجمهور : أجل!
Natalie! Natalie! Natalie!
ناتالي! ناتالي! ناتالي!
(Music)
(موسيقى)
Together we are free!
معا نحن أحرار!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So you would think that this is the moment in my life,
ستظنون أن هذه هي أفضل لحظة في حياتي،
the pinnacle that made me an extraordinary.
القمة التي جعلتني اسثنائية.
And it was an awesome moment.
وقد كانت لحظة رائعة.
I mean, I was on top of the world.
أعني، لقد كنت أقف على قمة العالم.
Ten million people watched the "Oprah Winfrey Show."
10 ملايين شخص شاهدوا " برنامج أوبرا وينفري."
But looking back, that wasn't it.
لكن عند تذكر ما حدث، أُدرك أنها لم تكن كذلك.
Don't get me wrong.
لا تسيؤوا فهمي.
Like I said, it was great moment.
كما قلت، كانت لحظة عظيمة.
It made for a heck of a profile picture on Facebook for a week.
لقد صنعت صورة رائعة لحسابي على الفيسبوك لأسبوع.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I had been extraordinary all along,
لكني كنت استثائية طيلة الوقت،
and I wasn't alone.
ولم أكن وحدي.
You see, even though my story was featured in this film,
كما ترون، رغم كون قصتي برزت في الفيلم،
I was just one of a hundred interns
لقد كنت واحدة من مئات المتدربين
who worked their tails off to make this happen.
الذين عملوا بجهد كبير لينجح الأمر.
I'm up in the air,
أنا محمولة في الهواء،
but the guy that I'm sitting on his shoulders,
لكن الشخص الذين أجلس على كتيفيه،
he's my best friend.
هو صديقي العزيز.
His name is Johannes Oberman
اسمه جوانس أوبرمن
and Johannes worked with me from day one in Chicago,
عمل معي من اليوم الأول في شيكاغو،
just as long hours, just as many sleepless nights as I did.
لساعات طويلة وبدون نوم مثلي تماما.
The girl on the right, her name's Bethany Bylsma.
الفتاة على اليمين، اسمها بيثاني بيلسما.
Bethany planned New York City and Boston,
بيثاني عملت في مدينة نيويورك وبوسطن،
and they were seriously the most beautiful events that we held.
وقد كانت بجد أكثر الأحداث روعة التي قمنا بها.
The girl on the left, her name's Colleen.
الفتاة التي على اليسار، اسمها كولين.
Colleen moved to Mexico,
كولين انتقلت للعيش بالمكسيك،
moved, for three months,
انتقلت للعيش لثلاثة أشهر،
to plan five events there,
للتخطيط لخمس أحداث هناك،
only to be kicked out the day before the events
وتم طردها يوم واحد قبل تنظيم الأحداث
because of the swine flu.
بسبب انفلونزا الخنازير
And then there was this family.
وبعدها، هناك عائلة،
This family, they didn't get to come to the rescue.
هذه العائلة، لم يحضروا للإنقاذ.
They couldn't make it out,
هم لم يستطيعوا الخروج،
but they ordered a hundred boxes of pizza for us,
ولكنهم طلبوا مائة صندوق بيتزا لنا،
delivered them to the corner of Michigan and Randolph
وسُلِّمَت إلى للحاضرين بميتشغن و راندولف
where we were all silently protesting.
حيث كنا نتظاهر بصمت.
You see, it was people like this doing whatever they could,
كما ترون، كان الناس يفعلون كل ما بوسعهم،
simultaneously, single-mindedly,
في نفس الزمن ونفس التفكير،
without a care to who was watching,
بدون الاهتمام بمن يتابع،
that made this happen.
هذا ما جعل الأمر يحدث.
It wasn't about us getting on Oprah,
لم يكن الأمر متعلق بالحصول على أوبرا،
because when I got down from their shoulders,
لأنني عندما نزلت من على أكتنافهم
the war hadn't ended.
لم تكن الحرب قد انتهت.
It was about that bill.
كان الأمر متعلق بالقانون.
Oprah was just a checkpoint on the way to that bill.
أوبرا كانت خطوة في طريق تمرير القانون.
That bill was the point.
كان تمريره هو الهدف.
That bill is what we had our eyes set on from day one.
تمرير القانون هو ما ركزنا عليه منذ اليوم الأول.
That was going to help us end Africa's longest-running war.
هو ما سيساعدنا على إنهاء أطول حرب في أفريقيا.
And that is what brought a hundred thousand people
وهو ما جلب مائة ألف شخص
out to the rescue event from around the world.
للخارج لإنقاذ من حولهم من الحرب.
And it paid off:
وقد تحقق:
10 days after we were on Oprah,
بعد 10 أيام من مرورنا في برنامج أوبرا،
the bill was introduced into Congress.
عُرض القانون على الكونجرس.
A year after that, it got unanimously
وبعدها بسنة، حصل على الإجماع
267 cosponsors in Congress.
267 شخص من أعضاء الكونجرس
And then one week after that,
وبعدها بأسبوع،
President Obama signed our bill into law.
وقع الرئيس أوباما على تمريره إلى قانون.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And none of us interns got to be there.
ولم يتمكن أي أحد من متدربينا الحضور هناك.
We didn't get to be there in this moment.
لم نكن هناك في تلك اللحظة.
Our founders were there.
ممولينا كانوا هناك.
They're the guys cheesing in the background.
إنهم الأشخاص الذين كانوا خلفنا.
But that moment right there is what made all of it worth it.
تلك اللحظة بالتحديد هي ما جعلت الأمر يستحق كل ذلك.
It's what a hundred thousand anonymous extraordinaries
هي ما جعل مائة ألف من المميزين المجهولين
worked for so hard to make that happen.
يعملون بجهد لتحقيق ذلك.
You know, the Oprah moments,
أتعلمون، تلك اللحظات مع أوبرا،
they prove that the supposedly impossible can be done.
أثبتت أن ما يفترض أن يكون مستحيلا هو قابل للتحقق.
They inspire us. They boost our confidence.
لقد ألهمونا. شحنوا ثقتنا.
But the moment isn't a movement.
لكن اللحظة ليست الحركة.
Even a lot of those moments strung together don't fuel a movement.
حتى الكثير من تلك اللحظات مع بعضها لا تنتج حركة.
What fuels a movement are the anonymous extraordinaries behind it.
ما ينتج الحركة هم الناس المجهولين والمميزين في الخلف.
You know, for me, what kept me pushing on through the rescue
كما تعلمون، بالنسبة لي، ما حافظ على تحفيزي خلال حملة الإنقاذ
was the thought of those child soldiers.
هم أولئك الأطفال المجندين.
It became personal. I was able to go to Africa at one point.
أصبح الأمر شخصيا. في لحظة ما كنت مستعدة للذهاب إلى أفريقيا.
I met these incredible people.
قابلت أولئك الناس الخارقين.
I have friends that have been living in this conflict their entire life,
لدي أصدقاء يعيشون في هذا التناقض طوال حياتهم،
and it was personal to me.
وكان الأمر شخصيا بالنسبة لي.
But that doesn't have to be what drives you.
لكن هذا لا يجب أن يكون الشيء الذي دفعني.
You know, you may want to be the next Shepard Fairey
كما تعلمون، قد تود لو تكون "شيبرد فاري" القادم.
or the next JK Rowling
أو جي كيه رولنج القادم
or the next whoever.
أو أيٍّ ممن تريد.
It doesn't matter, but whatever you want,
هذا لا يهم، لكن بغض النظر عمن تريد أن تكون،
chase after it with everything that you have --
أصبو إليه بكل قواك...
not because of the fame or the fortune,
ليس بسبب الشهرة أو الثروة،
but solely because that's what you believe in,
لكن فقط بسبب ما تؤمن به،
because that's what makes your heart sing.
لأن هذا ما يجعل قلبك يغني.
That's what your dance is.
هذه هي رقصتك.
That's what is going to define our generation,
هذا ما سيحدد معالم جيلنا،
when we start chasing and fighting after the things that we love
عندما بدأنا ملاحقة والنضال من أجل الأمور التي نحب
and that we want to fight for.
وهذا ما نريد النضال لأجله.
I cared too much in high school about what people thought about me.
اهتممت كثيرا في مرحلة الثانوية بنظرة الناس اتجاهي.
That's what so awesome about this conference,
هذا ما يميز هذه المحادثة،
is so many of you are so young.
أن الكثير منكم صغار السن.
Find that thing that inspires you that you love, and just chase after it.
ابحث على الأمر الذي يلهمك وتحبه، واسعى خلفه.
You know, fight for that,
حارب من أجله،
because that is what is going to change this world
لأن هذا هو ما سيغير هذا العالم
and that is what defines us.
وهو ما سيحدد من نحن.
Despite what people think,
بغض النظر عن تفكير الناس،
my Oprah moments, my being on TED, doesn't define me,
لحظاتي مع أوبرا، وجودي في TED، لا يحدد من أنا،
because if you were to follow me home to LA,
لأنكم لو ذهبتم معي إلى البيت في لوس أنجلوس،
you would see me waiting tables and nannying to pay the bills
ستروني أنني خادمة وأربي الأطفال على دفع الفواتير
as I chase after my dream of becoming a filmmaker.
خلال سعيي خلف حلمي لأصبح صانعة أفلام.
In the small, anonymous, monotonous
تصرفات كل يوم
every-single-day acts,
الصغيرة، والمجهولة، والرتيبة
I have to remind myself to be extraordinary.
علي أن أذكر نفسي بأن أكون متميزة.
And believe me, when the door is closed and the cameras are off,
وصدقوني، عندما تكون الأبواب مغلقة والكاميرات مطفآة،
it's tough.
فإن الأمر صعب.
But if there's one thing that I want to drive home to you,
لكن إن كان هناك شيء واحد أريدكم تذكره بالعودة إلى البيت.
one thing that I can say, not just to you but to myself,
شيء واحد أستطيع قوله، ليس فقط لكم ولكن لنفسي أيضا،
is that it is the acts that make us extraordinary,
أن الأفعال هي ما يجعلنا متميزين،
not the Oprah moments. Thank you.
وليست لحظات نلتقي فيها مع أوبرا. شكرا جزيلا لكم.